## **JACK ERSBO**

MADISON, WISCONSIN

jhersbo@gmail.com | (262)441-3564 | jackersbo.com | github.com/jhersbo | linkedin.com/in/jack-henry-ersbo/

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I am a former academic researcher who is making the transition to web development. During my time in research, I was part of a lab which studied many facets of human phonation (voice). With a great PI, team, and other staff supporting me, I was successful in publishing articles in notable medical journals and giving presentations to disseminate our research. Due to the engineering nature of our lab, I was exposed to lots of interesting tech including custom GUIs, data collection interfaces, and machine learning algorithms. This sparked my intention to transition into web development.

#### **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN, COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING

ThriveDX Web Development Bootcamp

Courses: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript/TypeScript, Python, React.js.

evaluation in the second of th

**UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN-MADISON** 

Bachelor of Science, Neurobiology Certificate, Global Health Studies

**SKILLS PROFILE** 

**Development Technologies:** Node.js, Flask, React.js, Express.js

**Databases:** PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB (NoSQL)

Deployment Tools: AWS, Heroku, Netlify

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, Python

**PROJECT EXPERIENCE** 

#### ChenequaFarms.com | Freelance

November 2022 - current

Madison, WI

Madison, WI

May 2020

May 2022

- Stack: Node.js, React, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Sequelize.js
- Building an enterprise-scale application for a family farm. App functions as a point-of-service.
- Responsible for all phases of development, unit testing, deployment, and coordination with the client.

## **LISTR | Independent Project**

- Stack: Node.js, React, Express.js, PostgresSQL, Sequelize.js
- A list and task-planning application with full REST/CRUD functionality. Originally built for my partner and I to use for our weekly trips to the grocery store. Thus, it is mobile-only.
- Found here: <a href="https://listr-ersbo.herokuapp.com/">https://listr-ersbo.herokuapp.com/</a>

### **PARKSPOT | Independent Project**

- Stack: Node.js, React, Express.js, PostgresSQL, Sequelize.js
- A marketplace for listing and reserving parking spots in people's yards. Its primary use-case is during college football season here in Madison, WI. Mobile and desktop supported.
- Found here: <a href="https://parkspot-client.herokuapp.com/">https://parkspot-client.herokuapp.com/</a>

## **MARSHES' MELONS | Independent Project**

- Stack: Node.js, JavaScript, jQuery, Phaser.js, Express.js, MongoDB
- A platformer-style browser game that utilizes Phaser.js, a game engine library, in conjunction with the HTML canvas element and other DOM manipulation methods. Desktop only.
- Found here: <a href="https://jhersbo.github.io/marshes-melons/">https://jhersbo.github.io/marshes-melons/</a>

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### Univ. Wisconsin Laryngeal Physiology Lab, Madison, WI

May 2020 - July 2022

Lab Manager and Senior Research Specialist

- Fast-paced, engineering-driven, collaborative environment.
- Managed up to 25 undergraduate researchers; tracked their progress and gave direction when they needed help. Hiring manager for students and full-time staff.
- Key person in grants administration consisting of reports to the NIH, PHS, and other funding agencies (3 RO1 grants totaling over \$4 million in total support).
- Oversaw the production and publication of over a dozen scientific articles. Helped coordinate academic collaborations with other universities, both domestic and foreign.
- Helped maintain the lab's codebases (primarily in Python and C#). Built small web applications to help with human subject recruitment and data collection.
- Published my own work—an example below:
  Fang, Yanqing; Zhang, Kun; Ersbo, Jack H.; Chen, Bing. The Impact of the Frequency-Specific Preoperative Sensorineural Hearing Loss to Postoperative Overclosure of Bone Conduction in Stapedotomy. Otology & Neurotology: October 2021 Volume 42 Issue 9 p 1314-1322

# Univ. Wisconsin Laryngeal Physiology Lab, Madison, WI

April 2018 - May 2020

Undergraduate Research Assistant

- Pursued both independent and collaborative research. Led one of the lab's research teams.
- Specialized in instrumentation and imaging. Adapted new techniques for studying laryngeal tissue composition including XCLARITY, MYOCLEAR, OrgoClear (proprietary), Optical Coherence Tomography, Tissue Dielectric Property measurement.
- Published one manuscript and gave two conference poster presentations.